that's hello YouTube welcome to the
first fix the world Friday of 2020 like
you know the 2020 means of it being the
20s again 2020 vision it's like my
revolution I mean resolution is to
create I've been using the language you
put on the agenda so if you keep going
back to it to look at it that's how well
my memory is come build a cooperative to
create technology by everyone for
everyone I don't even know me beep and I
said that and that you probably get down
I don't think so that sounds more like
there's a combination what you said the
for everyone by everyone
no that's I think that's what she said
actually like smart snippets I say as
opposed to all that all the noise
condensation condensing it yesterday on
the periscope I mean most of it wasn't
anything but there was the one point
where the guy called in and was asking
questions so there was a point where I
was talking about Facebook like I want
just that click can I have like just
that two-minute clip and put it out
there that's kind of what happens
conversation I might figure out how to
download that I was watching a little
bit I thought it was fascinating I need
to rewatch it because I missed some of
it but I didn't put it on the agenda but
I did think it was interesting trying to
explain it to him and to see where he
interpreted differently so I I don't
know if you're up to up for it but I
would like to maybe even craft that a
little bit more I have some ideas yeah
I'm up for their first later write
anything and everything that is
radiantly tech cooperative it's for
everyone a microphone yeah I think we
are doing in 2020 which is like what are
you doing tomorrow it's gonna be a big
first step I mean doing the meta project
project crazy it's gonna hopefully
catalyze not on the first day but
something out of it it's gonna be like
oh we all have the same problems how and
that he was like oh you're gonna
piggyback on their funding and I was
like
that's not what I'm saying crowdsource
funding like we all have the same
problem so if we can figure out funding
one time if we can figure out marketing
one time for one meta project that can
you know mean then give grants out and
like if people better want to say worth
it but that seems wrong but people who
are worth it ubi right like interviewing
or having a conversation with James
Jones yesterday from Hume spawn I was
like like if I was a millionaire I would
be paying $50,000 a year to sit and do
this because this is very important and
having people be able to work on
projects that are important to them
without needing to worry you know more
foods coming from it's like that's what
we I don't necessarily that's what we
need to be doing but as a society that's
a we need not having these one-off
Kickstarter accounts and like how do you
find how do you get enough patreon
supporters like what are who are a dozen
people who are changing the world who
aren't you on must who we could support
and actually have amazing projects of
them help them crowdfunding
crowdsourcing to the next roadblock and
an extra minute yes yeah reduce the
friction for all other people that want
to make the world a better place I mean
I have my vision but that's that's my
vision that's not our vision that's not
something that's like from the ground up
from like how do we fund it and that's
what I were integrating the space and
being part of the conversation of like
what does a technology company look like
that we run together that's today this
morning's conversation was supposed to
be with just four about fractal
democracy I don't know if you saw his
posting game on it they got my instead
it yeah I love the math and like the
people part I'm like I don't think art
works but I love fractal and like
exponential growth young but like that's
where with this I was like well I'll
just find ten people and they'll find
ten people and they'll find ten people
it doesn't work that way because ten
people all ten of them don't know ten
people who know ten we don't defend
people one in ten people knows hundred
people right and then that's actually
how it works but we've rescheduled my
Congress
next Wednesday so instead of it being
right before our board convenes right
before my Omega rural conversation but
that's life now
conversation upon conversations so do
you want do you mind if I share kind of
my ideas on a little bit more phrasing
so I was thinking that really our focus
I want to make sure that we're enticing
to people that aren't techies aren't
developers right because I think that's
the audience that we really need to
build because you know if they have the
funding then you can always hire devs
it'd be nice to have passionate devs but
you can always hire people so we use the
term build a cooperative I was just
wondering if there's a way to say I mean
really what it is
it's kind of a community right that then
I don't know here's a bad right a
brainstorms and funds you know
technology that is for them and you
could say by its just wouldn't we say by
them afraid that people are thinking
that it'd be more attractive to just
developers than to the average person we
want to make sure it's enticing to the
average person yes no and that's the
difficulty with a lot of the language
it's like like I started when I'm like
we can create a technology company that
will save developing for like oh yeah
cool that's not a thing that's won't
work don't know like how do I give you
all of this vision in one sentence it's
not gonna happen it's like yeah
technology's powerful it's risky and
it's more powerful and less risky
together and we can do basically
everything and anything with it and do
it in a I think away so I mean language
is not is the part that I struggle with
cause in it and it is is really the
hardest part I think it's just hard in
all the
startups I've been a part of and
initiatives similar to this but you know
very different ideas but the idea of
having someone who wants to make a
positive change in the world it's always
it always comes down to finding out how
to say it the way the people understand
butts short enough that they're they
have attention or at least yeah I giving
them a short enough message that though
then interested in learning more yeah no
absolutely and I know that that's where
with all of these places that I fall
short
the beauty of a cooperative is other
people don't write other people are
better at crafting language other people
are better at the marketing other people
are better at the tech the actual making
of the tech and all of those things and
it's about finding the right people at
the right time and rather than finding
us that I'm just coming on board and
that is not stopping them from doing
that which is what I've done in the past
so Michael I don't even know how to
craft the message so you can craft it
better right so it's like figuring out
how to mess up and work with people at
work you saw the post on getting beat
with someone who commented about kind of
voting on what we're doing for the
project raising which I mean we've had
all of those conversations like yeah
I'll put it out there in a pool and
people don't vote on it and people don't
like we're just gonna do it like if it's
a game D person and they have a project
I don't much care what their project is
maybe I will if someone shows up with
you know drone strikes as their okay no
we're not game B but that it's more
about the people right how do we support
the people that have a project and then
how do we create the men of thing that
supports all the the projects and wait
it's powerful for the individual come up
with the idea and the groups that
surround them yeah I guess yeah part of
what we're doing is is helping them with
the marketing thing or we're giving them
a space to be heard and they could build
that if it's an idea that that does
spark interest and hopefully we'll be
helping them also if they want to craft
that narrative in these meetings by just
simply asking questions and clarifying
things so so yeah we're already doing
that part of the community
tackling they'll kind of the
Marketing it's gotta be a better word
than marketing but the marketing issue
yeah like getting people who want to
know about you to know about you people
who want to help to know about how they
can help you not convincing people they
need to help you or convincing people
you're a solution to a problem they
never had yeah a lot of this stuff it is
acknowledged E and people have a problem
they maybe aren't aware of like yes you
use technology and they own your data
and they're gonna get more powerful is
an actual problem that some people are
aware of but don't think it was a
solution for and it's hard to market to
a solution that people don't know or
don't really care about so it's about
meeting them where they are figuring out
you know how that perhaps the message in
that way without crafting it too broadly
because this is part of what I struggle
with is like everyone needs to eat so if
we started with a food app we could find
possibly ten thousand people to it so
you know more easily to work on it at
the same time then we have ten thousand
very diapers very like who all they have
in common is that they want to eat
properly and so some people you know
like there it isn't there's a real like
the first project being and also
somewhat altruistic this is further my
good but the good of humanity as well is
a good place to start on like the idea
cafe or Yelper solutions or anything of
those or the meta projects that we can
see that these are people who already
have a passion for something they're
doing for a greater purpose then how do
we actually help each other I don't for
talking today about what that's gonna
look like tomorrow it's my brother who's
doing the first one for elections
there's no one seems to want to do
they're like I'll watch the first one
and it's kind of a good transition
because it was like our goal setting
group and some having to focus on wiki
elections to see what that looks like
what we were doing to what we are doing
right it feels good and he's not getting
biggie
so he's we can practice Omega rule but
he's not necessarily be requiring that
if that makes sense like it's like okay
good so I don't know if I'm good at SEO
make a rule with people's projects so
like what about this piece that isn't
working and
how to do that in it will make a rural
way that is helpful instead of a
deterrent right that isn't putting
people off their budget is it like oh no
one leaves a mess but is helping it be
stronger and more like I said before I
like it when people do that to my
project so I do it to other people's
projects not realizing that they
themselves might not really like that
because they haven't sat for hours
picking apart every hole in their own
project they loved when someone else
points out one maybe they haven't seen
her have seen that is not other people's
personality is so yeah like I said
before in game B I'm up there then the
naming and the wording of what we're
doing the project crazy I think works on
many a level I would love someone I'm
gonna put it out there will burrow in
the conversation tomorrow for someone to
do like a graphic or a thumbnail to put
up for them it's like project B cuz I'm
there's so many things happening on this
channel that are all kind of like live
videos than having I can fix on Friday
the live conversation I guess the idea
Cafe is on this other channel of it so
there's that much happening and in the
conversations I'm having with people as
well as just random thoughts that I feel
I need to express to the universe there
you go
a five-minute video format but also so
the together tech website is done more
or less it was one or two things I met
with her over break and it means you
knowledge it took her a lot longer than
she thought it would she's had a lot of
health challenges and but K she did it
and she did it for free and I like it it
looks good at the issue is which is
nothing to do what she did is that it's
old like it's the wix1 right so it's
like a very information focused tech
cooperative which is important we need
information we can trust and use at the
same time it's not as powerful as like
the connection piece as the you know
game be saying it's like Omni when
information is on you in but it's not
the same as you know like idea cafe or
the meta project
you know how do we have them to have a
conversation about these things but what
I would because we have them at a
project what I would love to see this
Friday heart evolve into is having the
conversations not just the two of us
hopefully with how like how do we find a
tech cooperative right how do we have
governance over a tech cooperative
there's all these people these amazing
ideas and how we can govern the world
right that was like a fractal Demong
democracy in these things and everyone's
like well we should I would you're
Jordan actually said I'd love to see
this tribe of 10,000 people I like
everyone so obsessed about finding a
city or a country to try these things on
instead of like a corporation's
actually is that like it's a place
that's safe enough to try and fail so
why not try our like having a mega mega
I make a corporation that has little
branches where they try these different
forms right like trying different forms
of communication different forms of
governments does this work doesn't it
work like I can only imagine sitting
down with fractal democracy I really
like the idea but I wouldn't want to see
it implemented across my country it
could be a disaster and there's a lot of
pros I can see even on paper the dough
aren't fixed by this in any more than
they are in first pass suppose so having
something was like a a musical note oh
sorry that's right um sitting down and
having that I was listening to or
reading a Wikipedia article and all the
different types of communication that
are like the World Cafe and trying those
and see which ones are effective for
what types of conversation if there's
fish full method which I think would
work really well because it's like five
four to five people sit in the center
and have a conversation and people come
and kind of talk people on the shoulder
and they remove or they come and sit in
the sea and then someone vacates a seat
so you only ever have four to five
people who are talking but you have a
much broader audience watching and that
is something we could actually try to
meet with a stream yard because of how
it works the issue is the rep like
especially with online the repetition
right there's like as soon as I want top
so know that like how rapid isn't
someone cut like you have to be seeds I
think you have to be sitting there for
at least 10-15 minutes before the next
person we kind of tap you out
it's just way too rapid and there isn't
any but there's um there has that we can
create technology that it makes an
effective communication tool for
everyone to be heard for the best idea
is to get to the top which is not I
don't think fractal democracy does that
because you have a conversation with
seven people but if you are like tier
five the idea is like there were all in
teams of seven right so like that's
seven at the fifth level if you're the
representative for that level you're
representing five to the power of seven
know the power five or something yeah
seven to power vodkas it's seven for
each level and but are you because
you're only meeting with seven plus
seven plus seven like seven times five
so like thirty five people and those are
the only ones you know and you're gonna
have nepotism towards them and not like
it's just like are buy more whenever I'm
not gonna have this conversation with
you
it's just to have this conversation two
hours ago but there's like to be able to
play and try different forms of
governments without like how do we have
a convert if there's four of us how do
we have a conversation that isn't one of
us leading it right that isn't will let
us run this by the believer right there
is no leader it's like how do we bring
our ideas to a group and how the best
ideas move forward and be able to
improve them together right without me
needing it to be my idea are you needing
it to be your idea like but only and
that we're going to do that because they
were us right like for human beings to
hear that in here but I could just a
little bit oh I guess someone hangs up
on you don't keep coming back it's not
with my kid at the moment she has asleep
over last night I'm sitting I'm here I'm
interrupted but not interrupted in
thought because what I was talking about
but finding like have even if people
don't want to be involved involvement
they don't want to gather tech to be
their project I do think people want to
have a say in how governance works how
communication works and just trying that
out that's why I think people do come to
the idea cafes and such
but I don't really know what that looks
like a part of what I wanted to do is
actually reach out to Jordan again and
have a conversation with him on like hey
how could this work in kind of a game be
space like how do we I wanted to post
something in the game be like how do we
run the game be group without admins
right not to like take over from the
abandons but like what does a space look
like without Authority with a needy and
there to be this central group of people
that you have to run like I don't like
this person they should be kicked out
like because there's a benefit and a
cost right like whoa the person they
want to be kicked up you don't want to
necessarily blast them right you don't
want to be like what here's why I don't
like them well then do you not like them
enough for them to you kicked out anyway
like what is the actual process of doing
that in a I'll make a rule away or it's
like wait what is the metric you need to
be to be part of this and if you're
failing at it repeatedly and not owning
your you know not groaning ohh moaning
what is the state that you know you just
have the conversations before those
things happen and to have the
conversation of like what game B is an
800 to a thousand root person grew so
fractal democracy we could actually be
using it right like we could actually be
meeting in groups of four and you know
like like seeing like how do we think
this could go and then offering it to
the group and having people ordinate all
that we can actually try things without
needing them to be global or mega cuz we
can't like the the two of us can't solve
the world's problems of the world
doesn't want the problem solved right
ourselves anyway unless people come on
board and want to offer what they want
as solutions work together to create
them and so the more like we're sitting
around and figuring out what how the
whole world should work and then making
the whole world work that way doesn't
work we need to include the world so
having a conversation that is includes
ten people and then that only is a
solution maybe first ten but we can
extrapolate and think about what it
would look like for millions or tens of
millions of people but only ever making
it kind of the size you are actually
like not thinking I know what 10 million
people need there aren't 10 million
Jubilees hanging out that all want to
say
same thing there's only one of me thank
God yeah what do you want this space to
look like like does that sound like it
resonates with you what I'm what I was
talking about yes I think that's well
together Tech and specific I guess you
could cover quite a few topics there
like for the game be space I don't I
don't think we have it anywhere like
real decisions but it's funny you really
only need democracy when you have kind
of a zero-sum game to some extent
because if you limited resources and you
don't there's nothing to decide as a
group it's really more like you float
something up and people would join if
they if they're passionate about it so
there may not be as much of a need for
that like at the game be space right now
unless we did want to like dissolve all
the admins and that may be something if
we had a path forward without that and
yeah that's something you'd probably
need a vote on and actually my you know
my future projects is to eliminate
voting in theory but it would you know
there'd still be a good reason to do
rank-choice voting or liquid democracy
or fractal democracy and fractal
democracy is very similar to what we
were doing with the meetings
it just wasn't regular regularly the
same people meeting and not almost they
could be better if you didn't have the
same people meeting each time where it
was you know groups of four or seven
meeting kind of randomly and then still
having that way of you know in the
fractal democracy one a person a
representative was the person that was
that was aggregating all the data up so
yeah those are all things to try and I
think even even smaller than a
corporation although if two together
texts there then it would be one but
each project
could be its own experiment with its
governance form assuming there's enough
people to warrant some sort of
governance but yeah also together tech
being a place to experiment with those
different ways and maybe that should be
part of the together Tech Charter is
that every six months or a year we
change the the way that everyone
aggregates right to try different
experiments because I still think having
together tech being one of the places
that we practice game B is a huge
benefit yeah yeah I saw and I didn't
mean that it's just game B is already a
population that's trying to create a
better world so there's been
interactions run like this feels
heretical to me even though it's not
trying to be hired like where they put
out a principles and vision it's like
well wait what if you don't agree with
one of them what like why and I get why
you need to have that but at the same
time and Facebook is set up very much to
have it mittens you can't believe a
favorite group it means right but having
the conversation of like what would this
look like not necessarily taking it away
just the conversation I want to have and
bravery we want to have that
conversation with together tech right I
want to have the conversation with five
people to say hey how do we run this
meeting that isn't immediate like it
isn't does it look like a board meeting
right like what makes this fun for us
what makes this um effective right
because part of what I struggle struggle
with my ideas come to me when I'm by
myself and generally started my kids and
then I write them on a paper and then I
can't communicate them I don't actually
know necessarily besides I know how to
have a conversation and whatever comes
off I could share it it's a different
process than being in group and being
individually but how do you those two
Mel looks there's tons of the I think
most people couple ideas by themselves
then have to get people on board with it
and so like what does it look like to
create something from the ground up
right this idea I have in my head on how
to fund it how to govern it how to do
all of that it's just not mine it's not
ours right and the truth is is it's the
seed it's not the plant and so creating
something that is just like what is that
word everything we would have to figure
out to run a technology company um my
mind more goes to things like funding
and marketing and governance because
those are important things to figure out
don't need to be done in the old way
right we don't need to have a Board of
Directors to meet behind closed doors
and decides things in secret the point
is to be more transparent and to have no
bird that lets not have a hierarchy
which means also owning the higher to
you right Odie it's inconvenient when
there isn't a boss to go to right our
boss to pass off Authority delivery like
well that's your fault you're the one
who told me to do that it's like we and
to allow for a culture of failure right
that we're and that was what I was
trying to talk about before with the
project tour on some was like well what
if this goes bad bad you should like be
picking which project when focusing on
and like how do you see this going bad
like what's the most horrific thing that
could happen with us being on camera
right like I'm so in this space at least
here like with this exact project of
getting it wrong I'm like every new
thing seems like it's the thing that's
gonna move it forward and it's gonna
explode if it doesn't it's gonna go
viral and there's gonna be you know a
million people we need to help create a
better world and it's not about that
it's about like playing in your own
space having what makes it fun for you
for me right and then creating it from
there and owning like we're not doing
this for a country where hopefully it's
gonna become huge but it's so small
right now that it is safe enough to fail
and what does failure even look like if
we're learning and growing and being
transparent about it so that whatever
iteration comes out you can see what
happens there's something very powerful
there so what I was trying to say was
that I want to have another conversation
with Jordan on ideas are not forgave me
specifically but he knows about the
technical operative and he's supportive
of it he thinks it's a great idea to ask
what he thinks this Friday think like or
whenever we do it could look like like
what do we need to talk about how do you
govern a small group without it needing
to be like without us deciding to have
power over the population right like
well if everyone 2x know you can and we
can ask them what would get them to X
but we can't demand they ever get there
we can't even demand people practice a
major rule right
we can have something similar in our
together tech but like when people
aren't what do we then do like what
conversations I just want to have a
conversation with him because I like
having a conversation people end up
watching
those videos more than they watch other
ones I'm wondering if he wanted to be
part of its no one okay
freeway conversation I think that would
be great
if I'm not able to be scheduled though I
wouldn't want to hold it up but yeah I
would appreciate being there yeah cool
all right and then we can kind of share
our vision and what whether it would and
it specifically for that so I would also
probably need help propagate that yeah
like kind of like a one page white page
what it is we're looking to do to invite
meant be great if you could come on at
11:00 a.m. on Friday and be live but I
don't know what that is a possibility I
won't put it forward for him for the
first one I like for the first option
and then otherwise I will say like one
when doing are available we hit him up
after we have I mean now I don't know if
you want to what ideas to do one or two
even though the his would be different
and we have the project think it might
make him more comfortable yeah if he if
he knows this is I mean he's aware of
everything going on but if he sees that
this is what we did with your brother's
one then I don't know the person I think
I told you the person who is next
thank you mention it somewhere J cousins
and I don't know what his project is and
I deserve because I wrote out the one
for wicky-wicky luncheons it's like
we're doing wiki elections I've yet to
get I didn't ask him to get okay we want
him aspirations you know they're three
aspiration so then we want that like
written in the comments people to see it
before us or the description before they
started the ideal but it's not necessary
but yeah you know what J cuz it's
project is but I was like he was the
first one to comment he didn't want to
go on for it so he's going on eleven and
then um there was the person who
commented on it was like I would love to
have a brainstorming space for people
who don't have projects right I'm like
that's literally what I want to do is
like how do we create something from
like the ground up so I was like that's
a project and of itself how do we
brainstorm about brainstorm right so
that's one and the beauty is any of them
can go like
weakly wrong is what it they don't read
any of it we get in an argument like
there is no perfectly wrong yeah or
skates example not how to do a mega roll
why can you be you know 30 seconds here
a few minutes there it's important it's
important to know when you're not
practicing it and be brought back to it
and so um so yeah so I will add Allah
wait well we had a couple weeks that'll
help me get language figured out anyway
and then reach out to Jordan Hall again
to UM to ask about he also had mentioned
in our conversation that's on this
channel
previously he knows people who are like
in the space of the World Cafe who know
like all of that stuff I don't everybody
called him I'd have to go back and look
and offered to put me in touch with them
and I've not followed up but following
up on that nasty yeah how does how does
that look right they might not want to
be part of together tech but having them
be part of a conversation on
conversations right like and they might
be interested in that's in our
scheduling software and we are first the
idea Cafe software because yeah being
I'll take a group of a hundred people
and break them down into you know it's a
four to seven and having them you know
chat I think would be something they'd
be interested in yeah and that was
looking at the Wikipedia for all the
difference are they're actually not many
types of conversations but the fishbowl
one and there was one other one I can't
remember that where I was like oh I can
see how these would be very powerful for
different things like one is almost a
almost a panel of experts right that
people are watching and then as you feel
you're the expert you can come sit in
the middle so it is more I think
introvert friendly to be you don't even
have people watching and and those that
want to come and speak speak and then as
part of its like that with breakout
groups and such and then with the idea
cafe like having just as scheduling to
learn like we were talking about that
helps you find the conversation in the
piece and maybe there's three different
types of conversations that were because
if the biggest part is the instant
schedule in our scheduling right getting
people in the same place at the same
time rhymes are same time around there
really it's come to think of it it's
breakout room it's asynchronous pair
breakout rooms right because the
breakout rooms that happen not wouldn't
have everyone else together mmm
it's off-off-off meeting breakout room
sorta yeah and then from there how do
you have an effective conversation it
funnels up but that's not beta that's
next right like the point in some
conversations about that and say create
hopefully a beta tool that helps me
facilitate that make that possible I
mean yeah I'm part of enough
conversations I don't necessarily need
this tool to facilitate the
conversations I do to my life right now
but I want everyone to have this
experience I want everyone to be
conversation so whatever is important to
them like right now there's this whole
Iran war thing it's about to happen and
the extinction rebellion and the thing
in Australia and I'm like I'm just so
sick of my newsfeed being filled with
problems instead of solutions like what
happens when there's a new I ran almost
war and you know my friend who's from
Horn and Iran is having a conversation
with me on Facebook it's like how do we
actually do something how do we actually
stop this war from happening that is it
marching the street because I didn't do
anything to do anything for the Iraq war
it's and you know it's maybe did
something for the Vietnam War after
hundreds of thousands of deaths ten
thousands of deaths at least and
American soldiers like it's just it's
not effective what we're doing and so to
have a space to have a conversation even
where it is just hey the president just
tweeted something stupid I want to talk
about it I want to have like not have
this pettiness on me and be able to say
hey how does this which is almost what I
wanted to do over the fractal democracy
was it how do we create a country like
that but how do we create technology
that utilizes that where when I want to
have a conversation I'm set up with six
people who also want to talk about that
and we can have a conversation and
brainstorm but we're not really gonna be
able to find funding with seven people
we're not really gonna be able to you
know I mean that's more of a board of
directors and funny but if something
like the Iraq war like the Iran war
that's about to happen something like
the Australian fires climate change
there isn't seven of us there's seventy
million of us there's 7 million of us
right yeah and then it puts you together
with another
some another group of seven and once
you're at a certain level you know you
have a certain amount of money to put in
as people are saying I'm putting in ten
dollars a month right and saying these
are the things I want to focus on and
how I was working at unwind talk did
jasper about it was that like if you're
putting in ten dollars a month whatever
level you're at you keep 25% of it and
pass on 75% of it right so the second
level has like you have 250 per person
right that's if you're meeting a person
you can get some some chips to eat right
like that's not but the idea is like
once you get to a certain level you know
you have the money to fund a project you
know you have something to do because
you're at you know the text here would
be everyone in the world but it like the
fifth sixth tier you have tens of
thousands hundreds of thousands of
dollars to work on something together
and you're going on that you're voting
where are we actually spending the money
you can spend your twenty five percent
all day every day you don't need to run
that by the group but the group the
level it's at you have to run it by
right so it has to not be content not a
hundred percent of people but do fifty
one percent of people want to support
this project versus this project and if
it's 50 50 maybe you split the funds
right like it was I'm not suggesting we
pivot and go that way just that it was
right
that's an idea have you heard of
logarithmic funding I think it's called
a logarithmic no but it's out anyways so
one of the ideas is that one of the ways
you can choose where your government
would spend your money but it could
apply to gather tech is that individuals
would donate their own money but the
government would contribute do matching
contributions but they would actually do
it logarithmically so that if two people
donated a dollar they would do like four
then so it was and they've run kind of
studies and analysis on that and show
that most of the time because of that
incentive to give more money most
projects get completely funded by
donations because people are
anticipating the government to help out
but in the end the government for most
projects doesn't need to help out just
having that incentive helps people feel
like their donations are going to a
Kickstarter type thing that's backed by
the government so I would say we need
$100,000 to make this if it happens that
we get 10,000 people who can attend all
we don't need the government but if we
get but we will get one person the
government's on findings is knowing of
interest but it's that it there's like
an in-between stage of like enough
people are interested there
logarithmically funding it what they
don't like so it's not like if we need
make a thousand dollars collectively we
also get a million dollars from the
government yeah probably not but it was
interesting when you were talking about
that you had like a certain amount or
that ten dollars where you're designated
where the funds go you know maybe that's
that's where that other the other eight
or ten you know up to make the ten there
might be some something in there to
learn together but yeah absolutely I
mean there's part of me there's a reason
I didn't pursue that in my own head in
my own mind in my fantasy world of
having it people put money towards a
specific project they wanted one that is
Kickstarter except but if we all
commonly own it there's nothing wrong
with the issue was a lot of niche
projects that are world life-changing
for a small group if people wouldn't get
funded having a way that you know
there's a certain pool of money and then
we can vote on how important things are
so like I know I wouldn't use that but I
can see how important it is for the deaf
population right so like if we need what
percentage is the deaf population right
well they're probably never going to get
together to fund that level of thing
because they're also going to care about
every other project but making sure the
bad that they that if you're a large
enough niche group you have X amount of
funding to make sure that you are in
fact going to get something out of it
right that you're going to get a project
that is important to you guys and how do
we utilize that project in or sorry that
I'm like the deaf community for instance
they can cover the project that helps
all the projects work for them right
like hey let's have live subtitles right
like that actually work I don't know how
they would do that but like not kind of
thing right think that's worth millions
and millions of dollars and it would
help not just the deaf community with
them and if every every community you
know speak English you speak any other
language you know you are trying to
helps a lot of people um I'm getting
sidetracked but that then the niche part
of it right that it was like well then
how do we fund that piece of it
I also don't know like in fractal
democracy it's one things as just
about is like let's say we were having
it with extinction rebellion right we're
people were like talking groups of seven
and they got to five tiers so we have I
didn't do a million dollars to spend on
a part of project extinction rebellion
definitely has more than a million
dollars they have enough people
contributing to them they definitely
have tons of money they're spending it
in a way that's like right so we're
putting ads on Facebook you know what I
mean like they're doing the old style
we're going out of the street for
marching we're disrupting traffic we're
doing these things which they think is
offensive right they think it's the best
option they have right now maybe it is
and that might be the option that's come
up with in 90% of the seven people
groups right like oh we marched in the
street and we spend our money this way
how do we get filtered up the one in a
hundred groups that's like or we could
just solve it right like or we could
just there might be more interaction
right and use those millions of dollars
to actually talk to some people who
don't think climate change is real to
actually recreate the supply chain right
to understand where is carbon and where
is it going what projects do we want to
understand this in what projects do we
want to have more of an effective role
as the voters as the consumers as the
workers that are actually effective
right that aren't this like how do you
vote those ideas that are outside the
box
even if they're ludicrous right like
even if it's like time travel you're
like well maybe like anything that's
ludicrous maybe gets a little more
attention so that we can have a
conversation about it see if there's any
merit here and then you know NAB and so
it's not just the status quo that gets
moved forward because it's what most
people think about right because that's
one of the benefits of the recent score
project I'm working on since everything
is reason based so if you want something
instead of voting if you want something
to rank higher
you put a reason for it and if you don't
think it should be put a reason against
it that those little ideas can quickly
rise to the top and if something if
someone puts in an idea until someone
thinks of a reason not to do it it ranks
pretty high
so one of the great thing about that is
that it does surface those radical ideas
I love that the audience it's like I can
pick a hole in anything and I can also
give you written work and those are
important things to not do not just not
really do it anyone at service you need
to know what could go wrong no we're not
saying frak the democracy couldn't work
is it probably gonna work cuz of
nepotism I don't mean don't try it right
I mean like how do we fix nepotism like
how do you how do I make sure I'm not
looking out for my six buddies that I'm
representing that I meet with every week
over the layers that are actually I'm
supposed to represent even more of right
so Mike how do we how do we actually
account for those things and I like that
because also people are buried with my
idea especially like it couldn't work
like have you heard it do you understand
what because no one's done it
it's like honest yeah like it's like at
this and at the same time they were like
solution if you come from a little girl
in Peru I'm like you're gonna listen to
a little girl in Peru it's not gonna
happen so yeah she probably does know
and you're not gonna listen because you
don't it's like you could come from
anyone but we're not gonna listen to
anyone and we do we need to listen to
everyone and not in a way that their
voice is amplified with stupid ideas but
like to be able to say this isn't to
have a reason not so that was the thing
with the Alpha a rally point that there
that I still couldn't find there where
it was like if you can prove it and
prove it but if you are just like kind
of on it and you don't have
another solution
like I said better than what we have
which is also everyone's like well it's
not perfect we can't implement that yeah
but it's perfect and we can keep
improving it so let's yes yes so I have
a couple of phrases here to run past you
as far as describing together tech hmm
so I was thinking first off just a
community people still work crafting
this course computer people a community
of people requesting and using software
for everyone as I don't like the word
requesting but
thing of designing is that people think
of like professional designers we want
to make sure that everyone feels like
they're contributing to the requirements
if there's a way to get the air horde
everybody in there again earlier anyways
and then like just community driven apps
and something like a call to action that
says join us tell us what apps would
make you happy or give you life
satisfaction or whatever they think that
is I like the the the idea behind the
first one the community of people
requesting and using software for
everyone um but I don't think it makes
sense to other people I don't think they
understood like what you said right they
don't know that one it's non tech people
like literally anyone can come to be
part of this are you a human
do you like technology come to it yeah
it's like we specifically don't really
need the tech people because we can all
heart and it's like what do you want in
it and and we cannot exactly hire them
like it's like that is what tech people
aren't necessarily like I don't feel I
need to make a make people's tech jobs
better right like like in this anyway I
feel I need to make agricultural workers
better that kind of thing it's like
there's enough people out there and we
have an amazing enough project if people
will work on it for the standard wage
they'll pick us first
right like especially they're getting
paid and it's not on contingency right
it's not home when we make money I'll
make millions of dollars no you won't
that's not what this is this is when we
make it our planet exists and humanity
gets better and better and so at the
same time if someone's putting their
life's blood into it or you know a year
or codeine they get paid they get actual
money for it because it's not a one hour
a week conversation that don't need to
get paid for it's amazing but I would
also like to get paid eventually right
like all of that at the same time but
that's not the money that comes in goes
to creating a project that's actually
needed and people are putting their
hours of time ins and skills to work or
so then to the board of directors that
our offering the vision but not that not
doing the physical labor of codeine and
making it look pretty in the
brainstorming piece we also probably
need NIM in person in person that can
coordinate having conversations with all
of the people in our new language is
gonna bring him yeah that'll probably be
one of the first either and slash
community one or both yeah so I
reordered on community driven apps
community of people requesting apps for
everyone that yeah that might still like
be there like the later kind of
description or something there yeah
somehow I want to say we want users
although users is a bad term an
efficient term is that it's a community
of users you know driving yeah you know
what they what they want yes that's
really Oh everything else comes from
that right mm-hmm
basically yeah everything comes from
that like funding the marketing the
ideas the power and whatever behind it
Oh joining to tell us what apps would
make you happy there was another word I
was gonna yeah happy is not great would
help you improve your life I think
that's language I've been using but I
don't know like one I don't think people
think that happiness is a possibility
you are really not happy when I'm like
we can have a revolution and it can be
easy and simple like it could be very
peaceful and like you can do the pieces
that you love and everyone else will
take care of the rest like no it needs
to be hard and if it's like to improve
your life right to make you happier to
help you eat better not perfect right to
help you like connect more with people
not here's your perfect order people who
will never have conflict which wouldn't
be good anyway how do you grow if
there's no conflict it's a little it
will just clone you and you can have
steak
so you to talk to I would say in
conflict the six of me yeah and I have a
problem with how I'm phrasing this
because it's joined to tell us so that
implies us can be us together but
usually when you're saying it still
sounds like they're not the main thing
joined to trying to tell us join to I
collaborate I just want to use all my
same old language join to collaborate on
what absol in your life yeah that's good
yeah I like that join to collaborate on
what apps would improve your life on
what it's trying to collaborate on apps
to improve your life mm-hmm I've got two
in there twice but I can I can workshop
that a little bit more than this is not
for this exact thing but if you can
craft it into the language there's what
we are doing is non-hierarchical right
like as much as we were gonna be a board
is it we're gonna work we're gonna take
on responsibility for creating things
for other people it's not on us right
like if you see something that isn't
being done and we're not doing it your
job isn't to tell us and make us do it
your job is to do it yourself right your
job is to help us craft how it gets done
like to take ownership right that like
we all are actual owners of this thing
which means there is no other to pass
off responsibility to we're all
responsible and that does not come
naturally to people in any way like then
just do it I'm like that's not what this
is like this is not I can just do it and
give it to I'm not Elon Musk this is not
gonna be that and I'm not gonna make
hundreds of millions of dollars out of
it it's going to be something we create
together or not at all can't you know
that it's like you're empowered comes at
a cost and a benefit right like or our
to create this technology company is
like everyone is empowered he can't
posit office you can't well the Board of
Directors didn't do that right well they
were on camera
for you to watch did you suggest it did
did we have a way to upload it you get
lost in the comments all the comments
like you know that um how do we actually
and I assume collaborate on apps see I'm
thinking does that still make people
think that they have to be like a
designer or developer or marketing
person perhaps you will use not design
but like ya know people just say tack
and they think which is so great that
I'm involved because they can see if
you've no tech is about it isn't a
fraction do you know how to turn on a
computer are you on attack you're
welcome
I also maybe say I know that's why I
kind of like request because that kind
of implies that you're not building
anything which of course they can but
that's not the that's not what we're
asking them to do join to request apps
to improve your life maybe instead I've
just collaborate sounds great but I'm
afraid it it implies that they'll be
building them yes it's gotta be a better
word than requests but I would to
thesaurus I'm actually putting this or a
brainstorm through thesaurus at the
moment
let's put collaborate that's the man
my whole word yeah I'm we use the word
inspire cooperate hook up hook up with
some apps hook up with some app
developers to create apps that would
help your life participate Co act and
that's not even a word concerts concur
be in cahoots co-produce do business
with it together blue one selves to you
go come glue yourself to check out to
attack cooperative I'd almost like to
use the word demand team ah
but that's too forceful call for you
said you already put in a request yeah I
had switched to request collaborate be
speak No so listen everything's been
co-opted by other I'm even holding
language all we have to do is come with
a whole new language right we'll start
with that yeah yeah click on something
on about ok we'll probably work out
better yeah or Elvis there we go is
there anything else so wouldn't you when
you had on the notes of the Jordan Hall
conversation that was with you wanting
to initiate a conversation with him
yeah and asking if you wanted to be part
of it if you wanted to be one of my
conversations that I have with people or
whether it was like a specific together
tech I think it also will let me stay
focused if you're there as well to be
like this is actually what we were doing
and I like the idea of waiting until
there's been a couple of project raising
sessions they say hey this is what we're
doing right and like we maybe I was like
an act I wonder if that brainstorming
one would be really good that's a long
time to wait three weeks but that would
be a good one to kind of link to them
because it would show what it would give
some seeds to that conversation with him
right because these are the things
people are thinking of mm-hmm how would
you thank you everyone for that yeah no
I see what you're saying I'm doing that
it might be good I mean who waited three
weeks for other things it's also yeah
the other thing is those things always
happened the day after this right so
it's like even if we did it the Friday
after that it's still like a whole week
and then we have whatever the fourth
option is after the idea is to like that
the project raising will meeting and
having a conversation about what's
working right what's working with the
person in the hot seat we need another
word for that but I don't hold to call
I'm like the project full
the barn owner let go home but I'm the
person who has the project right like
what worked and what didn't work which
might be very individual right it might
be this something that works for one
person doesn't work but once we have
enough of those under our belt we can
say hey here's what other people have
found people with this type of project
like this one did we did on the Facebook
posted it was a Kylie that she responds
she has that project about that was very
close together - together tech I thought
was it the one about him the commons
trust that one mm-hmm that's not the
name she had for but that may be it uh
yeah I'll go to that I was just thinking
but I wanted it specifically because I'd
like to hear more about her project yeah
no I because if it was that one I
actually commented down further and I
was like yes I'd love to have you on now
whoever had kind of done it on a
first-come first-served basis I'm like
you're too far down I have anything
scheduled that story oh yeah that was
ever gotcha interesting remember where's
Kylie has moving chaos global Commons
trust okay is that what you were talking
about yeah I'm pretty sure it was her
she had a like that's what it is she had
a different name one word thing for it
that but but yeah that's yeah to me that
had a lot of together tech overlap not
exactly the same thing but ya know I
like I like the idea of helping people
with their projects I like those
projects they're more huge and big but
like how do we then come together and
create something that isn't like one
person's idea because I don't think the
world's going to adopt one person's idea
it will adopt 10,000 people's idea that
we created together right like they'll
be at least ten thousand
to adopt it and it's very different we
are degrading it yeah I imagine that
through these meetings there will be
kind of a coalescence around an
interesting idea and and it just grow
naturally it will emerge right it's a
horse a lot a space I agree and I think
the one that has the most potential for
that is the brainstorming one the one
that there isn't actually the essence of
a full project because it's hard to have
a project and have people like open up
this piece right now this piece we
should do it this way
unless you're open to that because
you're like no I thought it all out and
it needs to be this way but no one's
jumping on board with your rigid
structure it turns out my accessory you
can I communicate it might be
interesting because it's a very I think
it's a fairly easy one to understand
that people are all like we need that
yet nobody really wants to fight like
how do you fund it right like nobody
funds we collections besides with
donations which might be how that how it
does go I don't even know what his
aspirations are what he wants up with
specifically but he'll figure it out by
tomorrow he works on deadlines like I do
I'm excited for our first one cuz I
think it'll be and I don't know if
anyone else is joining us as far as like
on video right I'm gonna post a lot of
people said they'll be listening so yes
yeah we're watching if you want to come
actually be part of the video part of it
yeah I'm if they want to ask questions I
mean I guess I can ask questions on the
chat right though but it would be better
if they want to I'm wondering if um we
can almost do it like a what's that
thing fishbowl one offered its my
brother where like me and you and him
are there and then having the link in
the descriptions people can jump in and
it might go horrifically wrong cuz I
might be a troll that shows
but I can see their picture down here so
I can see if there's one if we've seen
them before right it might be maybe I
just put that out there someone who's
been on ninety-eight cafe or the King V
space literally anyone who's here then
come in and you can be part of it and if
it gets to be too many me and you can
drop out write it like we can Adriel has
to be on there clearly it's the person
but me and you because III have to
physically be in this idea like in the
stream yard to be able to move people up
and down but I don't have to be on the
screen I can pull myself off the screen
and not just pose not be that person
which I've done in ideaa cafes before
which will be interesting like if there
is a bunch of people right or me and you
were there and he's there and the fourth
spot is just a revolving yeah I haven't
come in and come out yeah and I think
also having you and I to read the
comments and bring up the questions cuz
it's really hard as someone who's
presenting something they'll read
through all the questions and filter
that so really you and I should be
filtering this and you have to show them
right I don't I don't think my button
works to show a comment so yeah perfect
and predictable maybe once it's done
yeah there's no mustard dressing art cuz
then come back but yeah happy gnome I
can put it up on the screen like that
when it's something relevant I just want
to do it like I just like when I'm on
one I do it so I can read it better
it's why I feel like we'll put things on
this give me like that doesn't need to
be there but I can read them expecially
if I'm not expected to be as a think of
a participant in the conversation itself
which I probably won't be for which
collections because I've had a lot of
the thoughts already right and shared
them I don't necessarily have a lot
extra to contribute since I always have
something to say I'm sure but I don't
know what it is right unlike one city
with like fractals democracy we are
taking notes like I want to talk about
these things I had hundreds of hours of
conversations about politics and
technology with my brother so yeah it
might not be too much you two sharing
that and I'm more interested in what
other people up to just share on this
yeah how its received the idea with how
he's describing it
other I guess we can ask the two people
that are watching how do you feel about
that if there was an option to like pop
on here right now would that be
something people would like or not and I
guess the idea is just the people do it
if they want to here at the hour mark so
that's enough question person was taking
over um yeah I will put it to my brother
if he wants to have that like be a
fourth space of people kind of cycling
through or we can just decide that yeah
let's try that why not and tell him
that's how it's working yeah you know
really for tomorrow
I had a funeral come up so I may not oh
yeah yeah yeah no that is my reminder
just being that brother and I again that
would be interesting I think I'll post
them in the game be stay sane hey who
else wants to be on video to discuss
this project for the inaugural project
crazy right andum how dare someone buy
Bentley yeah I know yeah I'll see
depending on the timing I might be able
to hop on but yeah good to see if anyone
else wants to participate that's good
idea yes all right
and so operating that and then right I
will think about whether we're gonna
have a jump in jump out if it's just me
here it might be less doable for that
but I will we'll see I mean the truth is
there isn't gonna be 50 people watching
we might be rock words of five or ten so
yeah and even if it goes horribly wrong
it'll still be right so yep it's true
still learn what we learned all right
well we will say goodbye to YouTube hi
New Year welcome to 2020